newpaltz.edu 2006-06-15

# Welcome to the State University of New York at New Paltz: Internet Privacy Policy

**Definitions**  
The following definitions apply in this policy:

_Personal information_ : For purposes of this policy, "personal information" means any information concerning a natural person which, because of name, number, symbol, mark, or other identifier, can be used to identify that natural person.

_User_ : shall have the meaning set forth in subdivision 8 of section 202 of the State Technology Law.

**[www.newpaltz.edu](http://www.newpaltz.edu/)'s Commitment to Privacy**  
As a unit of the State University of New York (SUNY), we are committed to protecting the privacy of those who visit our site and making it easier and more efficient for individuals and businesses to interact with us. We recognize that it is critical for individuals and businesses to be confident that their privacy is protected when they visit [www.newpaltz.edu](http://www.newpaltz.edu/). You can travel through most of our Web site without giving us any information about yourself. Sometimes we do need information to provide services that you request, and this commitment of privacy explains our online information practices.

SUNY New Paltz does not collect any personal information about you unless you provide that information voluntarily by sending an e-mail, completing an online request for information form, or completing online applications.

In addition, SUNY New Paltz has implemented procedures to safeguard the integrity of its information technology assets, including, but not limited to, authentication, authorization, monitoring, auditing, and encryption. These security procedures have been integrated into the design, implementation, and day-to-day operations of [www.newpaltz.edu](http://www.newpaltz.edu/) as part of our continuing commitment to the security of electronic content as well as the electronic transmission of information.

For Web site security purposes and to maintain the availability of the campus' servers for all users, SUNY New Paltz employs software to monitor traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information or otherwise damage campus Web servers.

**Information Collected Automatically When You Visit[www.newpaltz.edu](http://www.newpaltz.edu/) **  
When visiting [www.newpaltz.edu](http://www.newpaltz.edu/), SUNY New Paltz automatically collects and stores the following information about your visit:

  * The Internet Protocol address of the computer that accessed our Web site 
  * The date and time of the user's request
  * The pages that were visited and the amount of time spent at each page
  * The type of browser, its version and the operating system on which that browser is running
  * The Web page from which the user accessed the current Web page

None of the above-mentioned information is deemed to constitute personal information by the [New York State Internet Privacy and Security Act](http://assembly.state.ny.us/leg/?cl=114). The information that is collected automatically is used to improve our Web site's content and to help us understand how users are interacting with our Web site. This information is collected for statistical analysis and to determine what information is of most and least interest to our users. The information is not collected for commercial marketing purposes and SUNY New Paltz is not authorized to sell or otherwise disclose the information collected from [www.newpaltz.edu](http://www.newpaltz.edu/) for commercial marketing purposes.

**Information Collected When You E-mail SUNY New Paltz or Complete a Transaction**  
During your visit to the SUNY New Paltz Web site you may send an e-mail to one or more of our faculty or staff members. In that event, your e-mail address and the contents of your message will be collected. The information collected is not limited to text characters and may include audio, video, and graphic information formats included in the message. Your e-mail address and the information included in your message will be used to respond to you, to address issues you identify, to improve this Web site, or to forward your message to a SUNY New Paltz representative for appropriate action. Your e-mail address is not collected for commercial purposes and SUNY New Paltz is not authorized to sell or otherwise disclose your e-mail address for commercial purposes.

SUNY New Paltz does not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13 or create profiles of children under the age of 13. Users are cautioned, however, that the collection of personal information submitted in an e-mail will be treated as though it was submitted by an adult. 

During your visit to [www.newpaltz.edu](http://www.newpaltz.edu/) you may complete a transaction such as an online application or a request for information form. The information collected by SUNY New Paltz, including personal information volunteered by you in completing the transaction, is used by SUNY New Paltz and may be disclosed by SUNY New Paltz for those purposes that may be reasonably ascertained from the nature and terms of the transaction in which the information was submitted.

**Disclosure of Information Collected Through This Web site**   
The collection of information through [www.newpaltz.edu](http://www.newpaltz.edu/) and the disclosure of that information are subject to the provisions of the New York State Internet Security and Privacy Act, the Freedom of Information Law, and the Personal Privacy Protection Law. SUNY New Paltz will only collect personal information through [www.newpaltz.edu](http://www.newpaltz.edu/) or disclose personal information collected through [www.newpaltz.edu](http://www.newpaltz.edu/) if the user has consented to the collection or disclosure of such personal information. The voluntary disclosure of personal information to SUNY New Paltz by the user constitutes consent to the collection and disclosure of the information by SUNY New Paltz for the purposes for which the user disclosed the information to SUNY New Paltz.

However, SUNY New Paltz may collect or disclose personal information without consent if the collection or disclosure is: (1) necessary to perform the statutory duties of SUNY New Paltz, necessary for SUNY New Paltz to operate a program authorized by federal, state or local law or regulation or otherwise necessary to carry out the mission of the college; (2) made pursuant to a court order or by law; (3) for the purpose of validating the identity of the user; or (4) of information to be used solely for statistical purposes that is in a form that cannot be used to identify any particular person.

Furthermore, SUNY may disclose personal information to federal or state law enforcement authorities to enforce its rights against unauthorized access or attempted unauthorized access to SUNY New Paltz' information technology assets.

**Retention of Information Collected Through this Web site**  
The information collected through [www.newpaltz.edu](http://www.newpaltz.edu/) is retained by SUNY in accordance with the records retention and disposition requirements of the New York State Arts & Cultural Affairs Law. In general, the Internet services logs of SUNY New Paltz, comprising electronic files or automated logs created to monitor access and use of services provided through the campus, are retained for as long as the campus feels they may be useful.

**Access to and Correction of Personal Information Collected Through[www.newpaltz.edu](http://www.newpaltz.edu/)**  
Any user may submit a request to SUNY New Paltz's privacy compliance officer to (1) determine whether personal information pertaining to that user has been collected through [www.newpaltz.edu](http://www.newpaltz.edu/) and (2) to request access to such information. Any such request shall be made in writing and must be accompanied by reasonable proof of identity of the user. Reasonable proof of identity may include verification of a signature, inclusion of an identifier generally known only to the user, or similar appropriate identification. The address of the privacy compliance officer is listed in the contact section of this document.

The privacy compliance officer shall, within five (5) business days of the receipt of a proper request, either (1) provide user with access to the personal information; (2) deny access in writing, explaining the reasons therefore; or (3) acknowledge the receipt of the request in writing, stating the approximate date when the request will be granted or denied, which date shall not be more than thirty (30) days from the date of the acknowledgment.

In the event that SUNY New Paltz has collected personal information pertaining to a user through [www.newpaltz.edu](http://www.newpaltz.edu/) and that information is to be provided to the user pursuant to the user's request, the privacy compliance officer shall inform the user of his or her right to request that the personal information be amended or corrected under the procedures set forth in section 95 of the [New York State Public Officers Law](http://www.tenant.net/Other_laws/Pubofc/pubofc08.txt).

**Confidentiality and Integrity of Personal Information Collected Through[www.newpaltz.edu](http://www.newpaltz.edu/)**  
SUNY New Paltz is committed to protecting personal information collected through [www.newpaltz.edu](http://www.newpaltz.edu/) against unauthorized access, use or disclosure. Consequently, SUNY New Paltz limits employee access to personal information collected through [www.newpaltz.edu](http://www.newpaltz.edu/) to those employees who need access to the information in the performance of their official duties.

**Cookies**  
The Alumni Bulletin Board and the Off-Campus Housing Bulletin Board both require users to login before they can post information to the bulletin board. When the user registers, they have the option to have their computer remember their login information ("Store Username and Password") so they won't need to login the next time they visit this site. If the user selects NO for this option, the Web page sets a temporary cookie that expires as soon as the user closes the browser. The purpose of the temporary cookie is to keep track of the user's information while they are viewing/posting to the bulletin board. If the user selects YES for this option, the Web page sets a permanent cookie with the username selected by the user, their e-mail address and their password.

This is the description that the user sees directly above the option to "Store Username and Password":

"The following options are only applicable to cookie enabled browsers, except the show email option. Information (a cookie) will be stored in your browser that will enable us to remember your username and password for you and how many topics to display at one time, should you choose so. The cookies are harmless and will only be used by this site."

**Disclaimer**  
The information provided in this privacy policy should not be construed as giving business, legal, or other advice, or warranting as fail proof, the security of information provided through [www.newpaltz.edu](http://www.newpaltz.edu/).

**Contact Information**   
For questions regarding this Internet privacy policy, please contact our privacy officer via e-mail at [webmaster@newpaltz.edu](mailto:webmaster@newpaltz.edu) or by regular mail at:

Privacy Compliance Officer  
Web Management - Public Affairs  
SUNY New Paltz  
1 Hawk Drive Suite 9  
New Paltz, NY 12561-2443 

_This policy was last updated May 12, 2003_
